Guide to the AIDS/Brooklyn Exhibition collection 1993.001
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Oral histories, 1992-1993
  - Morciglio, Adolph, 1992 June 1; 1993.001.08 (Box 11, Cassette 11, Box 12, Cassette 10)
    Adolph Morciglio was a person with AIDS (PWA) and a former intravenous drug user (IVDU). Part Puerto Rican, he grew up on Columbia Street in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn and lived in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood at the St. George Hotel in a special program for homeless PWAs. Prior to the interview, he'd had no major opportunistic infections though he had a dangerously low T cell count. He was formerly working as a paralegal and had been incarcerated at Rikers Island.
    In the interview, Adolph Morciglio speaks about his long relationship with drugs; both as a person who used drugs for 30 years and as someone who no longer uses drugs, as well the role that drugs played during his time at Rikers Island. He speaks about his early childhood and the impact he feels it had on his opportunities in life, his early awareness of HIV, and the impact HIV has had on his life, his family, and the Red Hook community he is from. Towards the end of the interview, he speaks about the need for greater action by the government and churches. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  - Morrissey, Karen and Ripp, Robert, 1992 July 29; 1993.001.09 (Box 11, Cassette 12, Cassette 13, Box 12, Cassette 11)
    Robert (Rob) Ripp is a gay man whose friend and lover Michael died of complications related to HIV/AIDS at the age of 26 on March 30, 1992. At the time of the interview, Ripp lived in the Park Slope / Carroll Gardens area of Brooklyn and was 30 years old. Ripp grew up on Long Island, and moved to New York when he was 23. Ripp was a member of ACT UP. Karen Morrissey is a heterosexual woman and Michael's sister. Michael and Morrissey grew up in Rye, New York in Westchester County. She has a child and a husband.
    This interview focuses on the life, death, and relationships of artist and dancer Michael through the points of view of his sister Karen Morrissey and his lover Robert (Rob) Ripp. Together they discuss serodiscordant couples, spirituality in the face of death, the lack of governmental response to HIV/AIDS, witnessing and supporting someone navigating the healthcare system, and the impact of HIV/AIDS on family, friends, and community. Ripp speaks about his understanding of HIV/AIDS as a gay man. Both reflect on being near Michael when he died. Morissey recalls how she came to learn more about homosexuality and HIV/AIDS through her brother and how she was awed by her brother's spirit in the face of adversity. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
    Four preservation .WAV files. One access .mp3 file.
  - Mulcahy, Donna, 1992 June 27; 1993.001.10 (Box 11, Cassette 14, Cassette 15, Box 12, Cassette 13)
    Donna Mulcahy, a white heterosexual woman, was 31 years old in 1992. Her partner Arthur died six months before this interview of AIDS-related causes. While she was born in the South, Mulcahy grew up on Long Island and moved to Brooklyn as an adult, where she met Arthur at a bar on Carroll Street. At the time of the interview, she was a lawyer. Before the death of her husband, Mulcahy had been active in the response to AIDS. After his death, Mulcahy was taking time to take care of herself.
    In the interview, Donna Mulcahy discusses her experience as a partnered straight woman not living with HIV in Brooklyn in the early 1990s, married to a man with HIV and an addiction to heroin. The narrator speaks about her partner's addiction and his status as an HIV positive person with AIDS. She speaks of a supportive family, a fulfilling work life, and a community of people living with and impacted by HIV and addiction. For this narrator, the AIDS crisis was at first something she ignored, then something she understood as about about people who used drugs, and eventually about other communities such as gay men and other partners of people living with HIV. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  - N., A., 1992 May 4; 1993.001.11 (Box 11, Cassette 16, Box 12, Cassette 15)
    A.N., a woman living with HIV/AIDS, was 43 years old at the time of the interview in 1992. Originally from Grenada, she moved with her family to Brooklyn when she was ten months old. After a break-up with her partner of seventeen years, she moved to California where, within a few years, she found out she was living with what she called "full-blown AIDS." The interview took place in the house she grew up in, where she lives with her family who help care for her.
    In the interview, A.N. discusses the life of a single Black woman living with HIV/AIDS in Brooklyn. The narrator speaks about her health challenges, weaving together her time in California and her time in Brooklyn. She speaks about the Brooklyn neighborhood of Crown Heights in relation to people's ideas of who has HIV, and who doesn't. She also speaks about sexuality, race, and HIV. Towards the end of the recording, an unidentified second interviewer comes in. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  - Norris, Barbara, 1992 August 19; 1993.001.12 (Box 11, Cassette 17, Cassette 18, Box 12, Cassette 16)
    Barbara Norris was a nurse working at Woodhull Hospital in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn where she worked at the AIDS clinic. Norris was born in Harlem, New York, moved to Brooklyn when she was married, and had three sons and two grandchildren. At the time of the interview in 1992, she identified as Christian whose experience with people living with HIV at the hospital helped shape her view on gay people, people who use drugs, and other members of the community.
    In the interview, Barbara Norris speaks about her experience as a nurse from the 1970s to the early 1990s in Brooklyn, whose work was deeply impacted by HIV. She speaks about the virus' impact on the people of Brooklyn who she saw coming into the hospital. During the interview she mentions differences she has seen between the AIDS epidemic in Brooklyn and Manhattan. Due to the narrator's long-standing perspective as a nurse with various managerial positions, she shared ideas on the role of the hospital within the epidemic and what ought to be happening. Norris also shares insights into the emotional toll the epidemic has on nurses. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  - Palazzo, Maria, 1992 July 30; 1993.001.13 (Box 11, Cassette 19, Box 12, Cassette 18)
    Maria Palazzo is a white Italian woman from the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn who was a volunteer at Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC) at the time of this interview. Palazzo worked as an accountant in Manhattan. She began volunteering for the AIDS Walk and other fundraisers, and eventually became part of the GMHC Buddy Program. Palazzo went on to do more outreach-based work.
    In the interview, Maria Palazzo describes volunteering with a large AIDS organization in a major city in the United States in the 1990s. She speaks about her motivations for volunteering, her interactions with fellow volunteers, and the reactions she received from the general public, her workmates, friends, and family related to her volunteering. The narrator also considers differences in attitudes and available resources between Manhattan and the Bronx. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  - Pearson, Mildred, 1992 July 11; 1993.001.14 (Box 11, Cassette 20, Cassette 21, Box 12, Cassette 19)
    Mildred Pearson was an African American woman from the Boerum Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. She was 61 years old and living in Williamsburg at the time of the interview. Pearson lived at Cooper Park public housing where she and her husband Rutledge raised 14 children. Her experience as a mother of a gay son who died of AIDS prompted her to join the Brooklyn AIDS Task Force (BATF). Pearson left BATF to establish a support group for mothers of people with AIDS (Mother's Love) when she realized more needed to be done to meet the emotional stress experienced by people with AIDS and their families. Mother's Love had weekly meetings for its members/mothers who also did outreach work in Brooklyn and the other boroughs. Mildred Pearson died in April 1994.
    In the interview, Mildred Pearson discusses being a mother of a person with AIDS (PWA) and working as a care provider. Pearson talks about discovering that her son Bruce Williams was sick, his treatment, and the home care that had a positive effect on his health. In the wake of Williams' death, she recalls getting help from a volunteer who had befriended Williams. She discusses reaching out to tell her story in support of the Brooklyn AIDS Task Force (BATF). She talks about forming the Mother's Love group when she was searching for a support group for mothers that felt more inclusive and diverse. Pearson describes her development into an activist. Pearson's interview covers topics of health care, social services, and the emotions generated by illness and loss. Pearson also discusses her faith, homelessness and addiction, and other deaths in her family. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
    Original and duplicate cassette tapes are not available for research use. Access to the interview is available onsite at the Center for Brooklyn History's Othmer Library and online on the Oral History Portal.
  - Post, Kenny and Wagner, Cheryl, 1992 September 25; 1993.001.15 (Box 11, Cassette 22, Cassette 23, Box 12, Cassette 21)
    Cheryl Wagner and Kenny Post, both white and from Brooklyn, had married four years before this 1992 interview. They met at a Narcotics Anonymous social shortly after they had begun rehabilitation programs for IV drug users. When they met, Post already knew he was HIV positive. Wagner was tested a year or two later and discovered that she too was positive. They had both experienced AIDS-related illnesses. Post worked as a cab driver, identified as an activist, and attended AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) meetings. Wagner participated in a variety of AIDS support/activist groups. They were both using Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC) resources. Wagner's 15 year old son was living with the couple in the Sheepshead Bay neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1992.
    In the interview, Kenny Post and Cheryl Wagner discuss issues specific to HIV-positive people with addiction and the programs established for this population. Wagner provides examples of discrimination faced by women with AIDS. They both discuss the healthcare and welfare system in New York City and the inadequate and unequal distribution of resources across the boroughs. They also discuss their relationship as two people with AIDS and the emotional impact of the AIDS crisis. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
    ACT UP New York (Organization)
  - Rivera, Dolores, 1992 September 11; 1993.001.16 (Box 11, Cassette 24, Box 12, Cassette 23)
    Dolores Rivera, a 51 year old Irish and African American woman, was diagnosed with AIDS after having pneumocystis pneumonia in 1986. Rivera was raised in the Brownsville neighborhood of Brooklyn. Aside from briefly living in Staten Island, Rivera only lived in Brooklyn. Rivera began using drugs when she was 36 years old after her children were all young adults and was homeless for a period of time. She believed she was infected with HIV through IV drug use, although she knew that her last sexual encounter was with a man who had the virus. After her diagnosis, she went into rehab and began outreach work within the Brooklyn IV drug-using community. When this interview took place in 1992, she had an apartment in the Bensonhurst neighborhood of Brooklyn. Rivera was babysitting her granddaughter while this interview was recorded. After this interview, Rivera served on the Board of Directors at Iris House. She died in 2004.
    In the interview, Dolores Rivera talks about her childhood in an abusive home and how that affected her adulthood. She describes her IV drug use and time when she was homeless. She discusses how her life changed after her diagnosis. Rivera shares her awareness of AIDS issues, how AIDS has impacted various Brooklyn communities, and ideas about what should be done to better manage the crisis. The interview is paused several times for Rivera to take care of her granddaughter. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  - Rosa, Luis Nieves, 1992 July 11; 1993.001.17 (Box 11, Cassette 25, Box 12, Cassette 24)
    Dr. Luis Nieves Rosa was 33 years old in 1992 at the time of this interview. He is a gay man and HIV positive. Raised in Arecibo, Puerto Rico, he moved to San Juan in 1977. Nieves Rosa believes he contracted the virus through sex in 1985 or earlier. He moved to Brooklyn in 1988 and lived in the Fort Greene neighborhood when the interview took place. From 1988-1990, he was a caseworker for people with AIDS (PWAs) at Woodhull Hospital in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn. It was during this period that his roommate and good friend got sick and died of AIDS, and Nieves Rosa was a care-partner for him. Later, he worked at the Hispanic AIDS Forum, and was active with Latino Gay Men of New York. Nieves Rosa has a doctorate in social work from the University of Puerto Rico, where he also currently teaches. In 2012, he published on the subject of homophobia in universities. As of 2014, he was serving as Director of the Center for Applied Social Research in Puerto Rico.
    Dr. Luis Nieves Rosa is interviewed about his young adult life as a gay man in Puerto Rico and the four years spent in Brooklyn prior to this 1992 interview. He speaks generally about the issues of Latino and gay Latino people with AIDS from his work with the Hispanic AIDS Forum. He discusses his participation in an experimental drug study, his experience as a care-partner for a friend with AIDS, and being a service provider and activist. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  - Sandoval, William with Rodriguez, Rita, 1992 June 11; 1993.001.18 (Box 11, Cassette 26, Cassette 27, Box 12, Cassette 25)
    When interviewed in 1992, William (Willie) Sandoval was a 41 year old Latino person with AIDS who was infected with the HIV virus through IV drug use. He grew up in South Brooklyn, one of nine siblings with a violent and alcoholic father. Sandoval lived in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn as an adult. He was diagnosed in 1988 after being hospitalized for a series of illnesses and psychiatric episodes associated with AIDS. Sandoval then lived at his sister's home in the Kensington neighborhood of Brooklyn. By 1992, he was often staying in the Lutheran Medical Center's AIDS ward. Sandoval was active in a number of organizations: ACT UP, Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC), church and education groups. Sandoval had to be less involved in these groups because of his health. He died on September 26, 1992 of complications due to AIDS. His sister, Rita Rodriguez, was 43 years old at the time of the interview, and moved out of Brooklyn in 1993.
    In the interview, William Sandoval speaks about the spread of the epidemic through Brooklyn neighborhoods, particularly Sunset Park. Sandoval compares Brooklyn and other parts of the city through his experience in AIDS organizations. He makes observations about the differences between Brooklyn and Manhattan physicians treating people with AIDS. Sandoval and his sister Rita Rodriguez recall their upbringing, Sandoval's drug use, and how the family has responded to his illness. They discuss how treatment can be improved and how awareness can address the stigma associated with the virus. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  - Sepkowitz, Douglas, 1992 October 23; 1993.001.19 (Box 11, Cassette 28, Cassette 29, Box 12, Cassette 27)
    Dr. Douglas Sepkowtiz was born in Oklahoma and is an infectious disease specialist. Sepkowitz studied internal medicine in medical school and worked in Brooklyn emergency rooms and Maimonides Medical Center in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn during the AIDS crisis. HIV impacted his work and his personal life. Sepkowitz had a colleague who was living with HIV and close family member died as a result of HIV/AIDS. Sepkowitz was an Assistant Professor of Medicine at SUNY-Downstate College of Medicine and is an infectious disease specialist affiliated with New York-Presbyterian Brooklyn Methodist Hospital.
    In the interview, Dr. Douglas Sepkowitz discusses his experience as a doctor in Brooklyn during the AIDS crisis. He brings up issues of ethics as a medical service provider and patients' agency in making decisions around care. He also discusses what changed as the epidemic evolved, including the populations of the patients he saw and structural changes within the world of medicine. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
    Two original audio cassettes. Two duplicate audio cassette.
  - Terson, Alice, 1992 September 26; 1993.001.20 (Box 11, Cassette 30, Cassette 31, Box 12, Cassette 29)
    Alice Terson was born in 1952 and grew up in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. Terson was HIV positive, Puerto Rican, and lesbian. At the time of the interview in 1992, she was a mother of one son and had a female partner. She was in recovery for addiction and formerly incarcerated. She worked at an AIDS service organization in Manhattan while living in Brooklyn. Alice Terson died in 2009.
    In the interview, Alice Terson shares her experience living with HIV and providing care and services for others living with HIV. Early in the interview, she speaks about how she had to deal with the negative stereotypes associated with the various aspects of her identity: lesbian, woman, Latina, former drug user, formerly incarcerated, Spanish-speaker. Terson identifies as an advocate and activist. She discusses issues with services for people with HIV/AIDS: how doctors need to build trust with patients, how prisons need to have HIV awareness and prevention programs, and the need for more Brooklyn-based services for folks living with HIV. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  - Weinstein, Ivan Keith, 1992 April 4; 1993.001.21 (Box 11, Cassette 32, Box 12, Cassette 31)
    Ivan Keith Weinstein was a 30 year old gay man living with HIV. Weinstein and his partner lived in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn at the time of this 1992 interview. Before he entered into what he called "forced retirement," due to his health, Weinstein was in the security industry. After his diagnosis, Weinstein worked on security consulting projects. He also worked a lot within the community, specifically as a stage manager for the AIDS Theater Project. Ivan Keith Weinstein died circa 1992.
    In the interview, Ivan Keith Weinstein discusses his experience as a gay man living with HIV in Brooklyn with a partner in the early 1990s. He discusses his opinion on the difference between living with HIV versus getting an AIDS diagnosis; his partner not wanting to disclose his HIV positive status; the lack of good services for people living with HIV in Brooklyn; and the impact that living with HIV has had on his personal relationships, work, sex life, and interactions with the medical profession. Towards the end of the interview, a different interviewer comes in and prompts Weinstein to discuss the first person he knew with HIV in Brooklyn and the differences in stigma and care in Manhattan versus Brooklyn. Most of the interview was conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  - Oral history summaries, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oral history transcript: Luis Nieves Rosa, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Oral history transcript: Barbara Norris, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Oral history transcript: Mildred Pearson, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Oral history transcript: Dolores Rivera, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oral history transcript: William Sandoval / Rita Rodriguez, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Oral history transcript: Cheryl Wagner / Kenny Post, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - [Photographs of interviewees], circa 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Series 2: Collected materials, 1985-1994
  This series is made up of materials gathered for research and display for the AIDS/Brooklyn exhibition. The materials relate to the AIDS epidemic in Brooklyn, as well as to HIV/AIDS in the New York metropolitan area. The series includes brochures, flyers, newsletters, obituaries, and news clippings. Subjects include AIDS awareness for teens and adults, support services for people with HIV and AIDS, including healthcare, food, and legal resources, and a few flyers with discriminatory messages against people with AIDS. There is one 1988 report on "AIDS in Brooklyn" from the Office of the Brooklyn Borough President and proceedings from the National Museum of Health and Medicine workshop "What About AIDS?," which Brooklyn Historical Society Executive Director David Kahn presented at in 1994. Many of the brochures and flyers are in both English and Spanish. Also included is one piece of signage from the exhibition.
  The series has been arranged by type of material.
  Language of Materials
  Materials primarily in English, with some advocacy and awareness materials in Spanish.
  - Spanish-language AIDS awareness + educational materials, 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Spanish-language AIDS support services, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AIDS resource directories: Brooklyn, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - AIDS resource guides: New York City, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - AIDS awareness and educational materials, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - AIDS counseling materials, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - AIDS counseling materials, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - HIV/AIDS healthcare programs, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Support services: food distribution, circa 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Discriminatory flyers, 1966-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    The "A Cure for AIDS" flyer was donated by Dr. Leonard B. Berkowitz.
  - AIDS and hemophilia, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Children and teens educational material, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - HIV/AIDS organization newsletters, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Memorials and obituaries, 1985-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The National AIDS Memorial at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine, circa 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - AIDS in Brooklyn: Report of a Public Hearing, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Museum of Health and Medicine, "What About AIDS?" workshop proceedings, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [News clippings], 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [AIDS/Brooklyn Exhibition signage], circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - [Paul A. Paroski, Jr. memorial service signboard], circa 1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - [Planned Parenthood poster], circa 1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Series 3: Donated materials, 1945-1997
  Series 3: Donated materials, 1945-1997, is arranged into 11 sub-series:
  Sub-series 3.1: Douglas Sepkowitz papers
  Sub-series 3.2: Barbara Norris papers, 1988-1993
  Sub-series 3.3: Alan Fleishman papers, 1985-1996
  Sub-series 3.4: James Frank Bruno papers, 1945-1992
  Sub-series 3.5: Frank S. Hewitt papers, 1985-1991
  Sub-series 3.6: Haitian Coalition on AIDS records, circa 1992
  Sub-series 3.7: Melinda Broman papers, 1986-1992
  Sub-series 3.8: Alan Haber papers, 1988-1993
  Sub-series 3.9: Gay Men's Health Crisis records, 1986-circa 1992
  Sub-series 3.10: AIDS Unity March and Rally posters, circa 1992
  Sub-series 3.11: Additional Donations, 1966-1997